

MATTHIEU FREYDER

Student in Data Science and Al

F-67340 Ingwiller

+33 6 52 37 51 90

PROFILE

With a dual experience as **Process Engineer** and **Pastor**, I am now training in **Data Science and AI**. I am looking for a company to host my two-year **apprenticeship**.

★★★★ Leadership and management

★★★★ Pedagogy

★★★★ Process engineering

★★★★★ Office automation

★★★☆☆ Programming (in progress)

★★★★☆ IT culture

in linkedin.com/in/matthieu-freyder-37ab7b22a

My complete web resume

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pastor, Église Protestante Évangélique de Bouxwiller (2012-2022)

Leadership and management of the association. Theological teaching and guidance. Coaching and training of association members. Celebration of services. Organization of solidarity. Relations with official and religious authorities. Communication, management of digital projects, accompanying the digital transition.

Teacher in Old Testament (2018-2022)

Speaker at conferences and training courses, teaching and tutoring theology students.

Head of youth association (2004-2021)

Member of the Board of Directors of the youth association Le Tremplin. Vice-president, responsible for IT, intranet, web and communication. Organization of camps.

Applied Research Engineer, Research Center Karlsruhe (KIT/ITC) (2004-2008)

Study of the reduction by primary measures of NOx emissions during the combustion of household waste in grate incinerators. Management of a pilot incineration plant (power 0.5 MW, waste throughput 150-300 kg/h). Planning and conducting measurement campaigns. Budget management. Data acquisition, processing and modelling. Tutoring of students.

Freelance Engineer (2003-2004)

Study of the thermal recycling of automobile shredder residues, on behalf of the Karlsruhe Research Centre and the BASF Group.

PROJECTS CARRIED OUT IN IT

- **> Training in development for artificial intelligence**. Validated MOOC Python from UGA/INRIA, free listener « Introduction to Deep Learning » (CNRS).
- > Network and system administration(Windows, Synology).
- **> Digital communication,** Web dev., Mailchimp, Canva, RGPD regulation.
- > Implementation of home automation solutions with HomeAssistant, monitoring, automation, data acquisition.

TRAINING

Master of Theology FLTE Vaux-sur-Seine, (2008-2013)

Process Engineering Engineer, specialty environment, Grenoble INP Phelma (2000-2003)

Master of Research in Process Engineering, Grenoble INP Phelma (2003)

LANGUAGES

French: Mother tongue

English:
Professional
German:
Professional

TECH

HTML/CSS Wordpress JavaScript/Python (in progress)

SOFT SKILLS

Good interpersonal skills Rigour Intellectual curiosity Teamwork